We don’t try to emulate what’s outside our window,
that’s the last thing we want to emulate.
Quay is a documentary film directed by Christopher Nolan.
In 2015, Christopher Nolan curated a selection of short films by the surrealist
animators the Quay Brothers to be distributed as a touring 35mm presentation.
The three films—"In Absentia" (2000), "The Comb" (1991) and "Street of Crocodiles" (1986)—were
accompanied by this brief portrait of the brothers at work in their London studio.
Self, played by Stephen Quay.
Self, played by Timothy Quay.
Quay is a 2015 British short documentary film composed, shot, edited, produced, and
directed by Christopher Nolan about animators Stephen and Timothy Quay.
The film premiered at the Film Forum theatre in New York City on 19 August 2015.
The film explores themes of stop motion, filmmaking,
identical twin, short film, فیلم کوتاه.
The tone is mind_bending.